This is the papaver Orientale...
the poppy,
這是一朵罌粟花
a plant which grows every other year
越年生的草本植物
It has long, saw-toothed
oval shaped leaves
葉是長橢圓形的，有鋸齒
...and scarlet or purple flowers
花分紅紫，大而美艷
When a poppy turns ripe,
罌粟果將熟的時候
a white resin like substance gushes out,
用刀子劃開，有自漿流出
which on aeration turns black
見了空氣即刻變成黑色
This is the raw material for making opium.
那就是制鴉片的原料
Hardworking poppy growers...
種罌粟花的人們
eke out a meagre existence
辛辛苦苦的只能換取兩餐
But the dealers in opium
可是輾轉經手的人們
...make a fortune out of it
卻個個發了大財
They purchase it cheaply...
他們由出產地廉價購出
and use it to make morphine and heroin
製成嗎啡和海洛英
This is then transferred to
all parts of the world
分運到世界各地
Nobody cares for a losing business;
賠本的生意沒人做
But as long as it can make money...
可是只要賺錢
...most would stick their neck out...
殺頭的生意也有人做
for something that's highly profitable
何況是一本萬利呢
So people get together
and form different rings
於是成群結黨，各立門派
to smuggle this illicit commodity
黑著良心，用黑錢運黑貨
Double crossing is not an exception...
黑吃黑的事件層出不窮
and so are floating bodies!
海面浮屍屢見不鮮
Goods are airlifted or shipped
他們運貨的方式有空投有船運
Those airlifted are dropped at sea
空投的扔在指定的公海海面
...to be picked up by boat
然後自會有人用船隻撈起
Those shipped are delivered to
a designated spot
海運的在議定地點對好暗號交貨
But the smugglers always get caught
可是螳螂捕蟬黃雀在後
...in the meshes of the law
強中更有強中手，能人背後有能人
There's a saying: A man dies for money
俗語說，人見利而不見害
A bird dies for food
魚見食而不見鉤
See how these unscrupulous traffickers
請看這些見利忘義無法無天的人們
...scheme against each other
是怎麼樣的勾心鬥角
How they play around!
如何的拈花惹草
Big boss, we didn't expect this
老大，這是意料之外的事
Fools! You're good for nothing
廢物，這點事都辦不好
You're a bunch of fools
都是一群飯桶
Do you think it could be Grace Chen?
老大，會不會是葛瑞絲陳?
Miss, do you want to buy shoes?
小姐，買鞋嗎?
I'm just looking
我看看
How's this pair?
怎麼樣?
It's okay
還可以，很好
Not bad
不錯
Quite nice
挺漂亮的
How much is it?
多少錢?
A hundred and twenty
一百二十塊
I'll take them
就買這一雙
Don't move
不許動
Let's go
走…
Big boss, we've got the girl
老大，那個妞已經弄來了
Alright
知道了
9 points. The banker pays
九點，閒贏
What are you doing?
你們幹什麼?
Let me go
放開我
Who are you?
你是誰
I can't tell you
我不能告訴你
We don't use our real names
連我們自己人也不知道誰叫什麼
I'm Ling Ling here
我在這兒的稱呼是玲玲
Call me Ling Ling
你就叫我玲玲吧
Miss Ling Ling, you've made a mistake
玲玲小姐，大概你們是搞錯了
I'm not Grace Chen. I'm Louisa Lai
我不叫葛瑞絲陳，我叫露薏絲黎
If you don't belive me...
對了，你不相信
get my driving licence and see
你拿我皮包裏面的駕駛執照看看
Louisa Lai
露薏絲黎
We probably are wrong
大概是搞錯了
Why didn't you show us this earlier?
那麼你為什麼不早拿出來呢
I was frightened out of my mind
我嚇都給他們嚇暈了
But I still can't let you go
不過有錯拿的沒錯放的
Big boss will be here in a minute
老大一會就來了
If we are wrong, he'll apologise to you
真弄錯了，老大會向你道歉的
What does your Big boss do?
你們老大是幹什麼的
I don't mind telling you
告訴你也沒關係
We operate a drug ring
and running into trouble lately
我們是一個走私集團，最近常出事
Big boss suspected that...
老大懷疑出事的原因
Grace Chen is the informer
是葛瑞絲陳告密的
He didn't intend to harm her
所以老大請她來也並不是想為難她
...but only to question her
只不過想問問她
Boss wants to know
where she gets her information
她的消息是哪兒來的
Even if I were Grace Chen...
就算我是葛瑞絲陳
you didn't have to tie me up like this
也不必這樣綁起來問話吧
We had a bet
我們在打賭
They said your bust was false
他們說你的胸部是打針的
I didn't agree,
therefore I wanted to find out
我說不像，所以我要證明一下
You
你…
Don't! Don't!
不要，不要這樣
Don't do that
不要這樣
So it's real
果然是真材實料呀
Don't do that, I beg you
求求你，不要這樣好不好?
I am not a man. Don't be shy
我又不是男人，什什麼
They said your walk shows...
他們說看你走路的樣子
you're shaved
不是水晶就是玻璃
I want to find out
看他們說的準不准
Don't!
不要這樣
Not bad. It's God's masterpiece
不錯，真不愧是上帝的傑作呀
Who is it?
誰呀
It's me
我
Don't open the door
不要開門哪
Big boss wants to apologise
for the mistake
老大向你道歉，是他認錯了人
But he also wants to sleep with you
不過他看上了你，想跟你玩一次
What?
什麼
He'll pay you $5,000...
不是自玩的，給你五千塊
and then send you home when it's over
完事送你回家
What do you think I am?
你們當我是什麼
Big boss admires you
這是老大看得起你
He wouldn't take me. How do you think?
我送給他，他都不要，怎麼樣?
You all are simply outrageous
你們簡直是目無法紀
Do you want a carrot or a stick?
我看你呀，不要敬酒不吃吃罰酒
When Big boss comes in,
等會兒老大進來
you better be nice to him, or...
你要乖乖的聽話，否則的話
I'll give you an injection
我會替你打一針
Then tie a stone up on your body
然後綁塊大石頭
...and fling you into the sea
扔到海裏餵魚吃
How's it going?
怎麼樣
It's fixed. Where's the money?
擺平了…錢呢
What do you think?
怎麼，好不好
It's not romantic. I was scared to death
點情調都沒有，嚇都嚇死了
That makes it more exciting
這樣才夠刺激嘛
Don't worry, I'll be nice to you
你放心，我不會對不起你
But I'm being unfaithful to my husband
可是我對不起我的丈夫呀
Besides my husband,
真的，除了我丈夫之外
you're the only man I've been with
你是我碰到的第二個男人
How do I compare with your husband?
我此你丈夫怎麼樣
He gives me love but you only want sex
他對我是愛，你只是玩
I don't want sex with anyone I don't like
我不喜歡她，根本不玩
If I don't like her, I won't love her
不好玩的呢，我根本不會愛她
I'll love you
我會愛你的
Is Big boss here?
老大在嗎
He's inside
在裏面呢
Who is it?
誰呀?
Your wife is here
大嫂來了
Madam
大嫂
Where is big boss?
老大在哪兒
He's in the club
在俱樂鄗
No more bets
來…買定離手
Bet, Bet
押…
Okay
我知道了
The banker wins
莊贏
Bet, Bet
押…
Brother, Louisa Lai's waiting for you
老大，露薏絲黎現在京都廳等您
Okay
知道了
Who is it?
誰呀?
It's me
我呀
What is it? An erotic movie?
怎麼，放小電影?
Don't you like it?
不好嗎
Yes, of course
好，當然好
But I've seen too many of them,
same old stuff
不過放得多了，老是那一套
I'm sure you wouldn't have seen
this before
這一套包你沒有看過
Okay
好
Let's have a live show first...
咱們先在舞台上來個真人表演
before watching the movie
然後再看銀幕上的
Damn you
死鬼
How do I compare with your wife?
怎麼樣，我此大嫂怎麼樣
She's no match from you
她怎麼能跟你此呢
She's loose and plain
渾身都松塌塌的，稀鬆平常二五眼
You're tight, warm, soft and smooth
哪像你…緊暖香自軟滑淺
You're a liar, if she's no good
我才不信呢，你說得她那麼壞
Why are you so afraid of her?
幹嘛那麼什她
For the money. She was Big boss's mistress
還不是為了錢嘛，她原來是老大的
Big boss? Aren't you Big boss?
老大?你不就是老大嗎
Big boss got life imprisonment,
老大打了個終身監禁
so then I became Big boss
我這個老二當然就升為老大了
I see
我明白了
So you own everything he had
於是以前老大的都變成你的了
And his mistress...
老大的黑市夫人
has become your wife
也就變成你名正言順的大嫂了
She's small where it should be big,
他媽的，大嫂該大的地方叫
and big where it should be small
不該大的地方大
I can't do anything
沒辦法
She's got the money so people
listen to her
朝錢在手，硬把令來行
Some day when the power...
總有一天等大權
is in my hand
全握在我手裏的時候
lt'll be a different story
大嫂…大茄子
Why did you switch off the light?
你關燈幹嘛?
So we can see the movie
看戲嘛
What is it?
怎麼回事
Who shoots this film?
這是什麼人拍的?
It came by parcel post this morning
早上送來個郵包
I thought one of my friends had sent it
我以為是朋友送的
Didn't think I'll see myself in the film
誰知道自己做了主角
Can't be that simple
沒那麼簡單吧
Is there any letter?
有沒有什麼敲詐信
There is a letter
信倒是有一封
It's not a threat or blackmail
不過沒有什麼恐嚇跟敲詐的字眼
It says that you and I can enjoy this
只是說可以跟大哥一起欣賞
It's also a payment for our fine acting
作為我們兩個人的片酬
And if you don't mind,
要是大哥不介意的話
There's a copy for your wife too
還準備送給大嫂一個拷貝
Never thought I'd be blackmailed
沒想到天天打雁倒叫雁啄了眼睛
Alright, speak up...
how much do you want?
打開天窗說亮話，你們要多少錢?
It's not my business
我們?怎麼會是我們
I'm not part of them
你應該說他們才對
Alright, what's the difference?
好了…別裝蒜了
I've had many experiences
大風大浪過得多了
But never imagined I'd be the one
沒想到在陰溝裏翻了船，你開價吧
Don't misunderstand,
I'm just the go-between
你可別誤會呀，我只是個傳聲筒
They said you have an agreement
with your wife
他們知道老大跟大嫂約法三章
That if either of you has an affair...
彼此都不能在外面亂搞男女關係
you will separate immediately
否則即刻分手
And all assets will go to
the innocent party
家產嘛，犯法的分文不取，是嗎?
So what?
是又怎麼樣
So they said this deal...
所以他們說這件交易
will go no less than 4 million
最低不希望少過四百萬
What?
什麼?
4 million
四百萬
4 million?
四百萬?
4 million
四百萬
4 million means peace in 4 seasons.
四百萬換來四季平安，四平八穩
You must know all men are brothers
四海之內皆兄弟
Since you got all the money from your boss
反正老大的錢也是因為以前的老大
after he was sentenced to 30 years in jail
判了三十年給吞下來的
As your wife,
大嫂嘛
you took over her as well
也是在以前的老大那邊接收過來的
I think you should take care of your men
照顧照顧自己兄弟也是應該的嘛
What if I refuse?
我要是不答應呢
Then you really will be in trouble
那可就要四面楚歌，八方碰壁
Alright
好吧，我這兒還有兩張
Here are two signed blank cheques
簽了名的空白支票
Fill in the amount you want
我就照你說的去辦
You better stay alert
不過我聽說最近外面風聲很緊
Don't blame me if anything happens
要是偷雞不成蝕把米，可怨不得我
Sure, but I want one with security
那當然，不過最好開一張保險的
What do you mean?
怎麼說
I want a check from your personal account
開四百萬，你的戶口
My own account?
我的
That needs my wife's signature as well
我的戶口是要我太大一齊簽名的
You sign your name first
你先簽你的
In case they can't cash-in your check,
萬一老大的拿不到
they'll get your wife to sign hers
他們會找大嫂簽的
What? You expect her to sign it?
Dream away
什麼，叫她簽?做夢
So it won't harm you to sign another one
所以簽多一張也等於自簽
What're you afraid of?
你什什麼
Ok, I'll sign
好吧，就這麼辦
But let's make this thing clear
不過有一件事咱們得先說清楚
I want all the prints and negatives
這個片子的拷貝底片要全交給我
Of course, it's "cash on delivery"
當然，一手交錢一手交貨
How do I compare with your wife?
怎麼樣，我此大嫂怎麼樣
She's no match from you
她怎麼能跟你此呢
She's loose and plain
渾身都松塌塌的，稀鬆平常二五眼
You're tight, warm, soft and smooth
哪像你…緊暖香自軟滑淺
You're a liar. If she's no good...
我才不信呢，你說得她那麼壞
why are you so afraid of her?
幹嘛那麼什她
For the money. She was Big boss's mistress
還不是為了錢嘛，她原來是老大的
Big boss? Aren't you Big boss?
老大?你不就是老大嗎
Big boss got life imprisonment,
老大打了個終身監禁
so then I became Big boss
我這個老二當然就升為老大了
I see
我明白了
So you own everything he had
於是以前老大的都變成你的了
And his mistress...
老大的黑市夫人
has become your wife
也就變成你名正言順的大嫂了
She's small where it should be big,
他媽的，大嫂該大的地方叫
and big where it should be small
不該大的地方大
I can't do anything
沒辦法
She's got the money so people
listen to her
朝錢在手，硬把令來行
Some day when the power...
總有一天等大權
is in my hands
全握在我手裏的時候
lt'll be a different story
大嫂…大茄子
Damn him!
他媽的，人面獸心
Ungrateful bastard
忘恩負義的王八蛋
He's taken all the jewels,
把老大大老婆的珠寶首飾美金股票
greenbacks and stocks
全都吞了不算
Now he's getting at me
現在居然又算計起我來了
I'll get him for this
老娘叫這小子不得好死
Madam, don't get mad
大嫂，何必為這種人生氣呢
Can't you see the truth?
您還看不出來嗎
He's a gentleman on the surface
這小子滿嘴的仁義道德
But really he's mean and nasty
滿肚子的男盜女娼
Since you have the proof now,
現在證據在我們手上
why not tell him to leave at once?
照您的條件，叫他拍拍屁股滾蛋
Take it easy
先穩住了
Legally a tape can't serve as proof
法律上聲帶可不能夠做證據
Adulterers must be caught in the act
捉姦要捉雙，捉賊要捉贓
We must catch him unawares
咱們得叫他心服口服
How?
怎麼個心服口服
I know big boss has a date with Louisa
我知道老大約好了露薏絲
...on Easter night
復活節的晚上在這兒見面
We'll lie to her that big boss...
到時候咱們假傳聖旨
wants her to wait in the other room
叫玲玲陪露薏絲先到羅馬廳去等著
Then we take off her clothes
然後把她的衣服脫下來給大嫂換上
...and let you put them on
先來個移花接木
Then I'll tell him Louisa is waiting
for him
然後我告訴老大，露薏絲在等他
The signal is three long
and two short knocks
敲門的暗號三長兩短
In the darkness he won't suspect
黑不隆冬的，叫他黑自莫辨
He should think you are Louisa
還什他不拿大嫂當露薏絲嗎
After he's finished...
辦完了事
We turn the light on
燈一亮，叫他原形畢霧
He wouldn't be able to deny it
還什他不認嗎
Good. I'll see that he suffers on Easter
好，就這麼辦，復活節叫他復古
Isn't madam great?
大嫂夠勁吧?
No, she's far inferior to me
夠什麼勁，此我差得遠了
Bluffing
吹牛
This girl has got a good figure
你看這小妞身材真不錯
She's no match for you
跟你此差遠了
How can I compete with her?
我怎麼能跟人家此呀
I am sloppy and plain
渾身松塌塌的，稀鬆平常二五眼
She's tight, warm, soft and smooth
人家呀…緊暖香自軟滑淺
Who said so?
你聽誰說的
I can see it at once
還看不出來嗎
Go and tell Louisa to get ready
你現在過去跟露薏絲說
Take her upstairs
帶她到樓上去
Okay
好
Big boss wants you to wait upstairs
老大叫你在樓上等他
Ok, I'll go up now
好，我上去了
Wait here, I'll tell him you're here
你在這兒等一會，我去叫他上來
Okay
好
Dance with Ling Ling. I'll be back
叫玲玲跟你跳一會，我去洗手間
This is big boss's wife
這是我們大嫂
You're Louisa Lai?
你叫露薏絲黎
Yes, I'm Louisa Lai
對，露薏絲黎
You're our present boss's wife
你就是現在大哥的大嫂
and the ex-boss's concubine
也是以前大哥的小大嫂
How dare you?
你敢
You bitch, how dare you mock me?
臭婊子，你竟敢挖苦我
You got a nerve
吃了熊心豹子膽了你
Take her clothes off
老四，給我扒光了
I want to see how tight she is
叫我看看她怎麼香，怎麼緊
Be quiet and lie down
老實點，乖乖的給我躺下
Make one move, and I'll stab you
動一動我就叫你三刀六洞
Stop
住手
Today being Easter,
let's make it sort of a buffet
今天是復活節，吃的是自助餐
So, do it yourself
我看你還是自己動手吧
Strip
脫
Strip?
脫?
Strip or I'll stab you
怎麼你想見紅呀?脫
Alright, I'll strip
脫就脫
Take everything else off
他媽的，把衣服脫光
Everything?
還要脫呀?
Strip, quickly
脫，快脫
Alright
脫就脫
Hurry up
快點
Tell her to put on my clothes
會兒叫她穿我的衣裳
and let him see her from distance
遠遠的在大哥面前亮亮相
Check around first
你先出去看看
I'll be ready
我這就準備好
Bring him upstairs
叫那小子上來
Okay
好
Keep an eye on her
看著她
What are you doing?
幹嘛
Dammit. Can't I even touch you?
他媽的，摸一下都不行
What's the big deal?
神氣什麼?
Big boss
老大
Madam is not feeling well
and has left early
大嫂說有點不太舒服先回去了
She said you can stay and have good time
叫你在這痛痛快快的玩好了
Okay
好
Dammit. You're weak with me
他媽的，跟老娘你就軟弱無能
You were strong with that bitch
跟他媽的臭婊子你就龍精虎猛
It's you who has a problem,
明明是你不行
and you said I'm loose and plain
還偏偏說是老娘稀鬆平常
Damn you, you ungrateful bastard
他媽的，忘恩負義，這王八蛋
Look who I am
你可別罵錯人哪
It's you
你…怎麼是你
Of course, it's me
當然是我，老大的老二不行
You said big boss is no good
老二的老二還不行嗎
When compared with him...
不見高山不顯平地
am I any good?
英雄出少年哪，大嫂
Dammit, you've taken advantage of me
他媽的，你這小子得了便宜還賣乖
You set up this trap to entrap me,
說，你們擺了這麼個圈套要我上
what do you want?
有什麼目的
Not a big deal
沒什麼
We only want you to sign this check
只想大嫂在老大的支票簿上簽個字
Sign this?
簽個字?
How much is it for?
多少?
Not much, only 4 million
不多，小數目，四百萬
4 million?
四百萬?
Yes, big boss has signed already
對，老大已經簽過了
It's Tai po branch
是大埔分行的
Alright. After I give you the money
好吧，不過你這小子可要記住
you must serve me 400 times
拿了我四百萬最少要伺候我四百次
400 times?
別說四百次了
I don't mind serving you 4 million times
就是四百萬次也在所不辭
Dammit
他媽的
4 million
四百萬
We're rich
我們發了
Yes
發了
It's them, is it?
是他們吧
Yes, there they are
就是他們
I knew they were up to no good
我早就知道他們幾個沒安好心
We may know a man's exterior
but not his heart
知人知面不知心
Those bastards have double-crossed us
這幾個王八蛋窩裏反
No wonder it came to this
難怪會出事
peace at last
這回天下太平了
What are you guys up to?
你們要怎麼樣
It's that bastard
這混蛋幹的好事
Girls! Come and entertain the guests
前院後院的姑娘們，見客了
Coming
來啦
Jing Bao, Xiao Hong, Bao Yu
金寶、小紅、寶玉
You two wait ahead for me
你們倆到前面等我
Okay
好
Hurry... you follow me
快…你們倆跟著我
pay some more
再給一點嘛
Master, I miss you so much
大爺，我好想你呀
Come again
下次再來
I'll come to see you tomorrow night
明天晚上我再來
Don't forget
記得呀
What's the hurry?
急什麼嘛你
Baby!
寶貝呀
Alright, come in
好吧，就這樣，進來
Come in, baby
快進來，寶貝
Let me close the door first
讓我先關門
So big
好大
Come on
來嘛
Don't forget to bring me sweets
有空來呀，別忘了給我帶糖來
I really miss you
你可來了，都不知道人家多想你
My wife won't let me go out
老婆看得緊，我從後門溜出來的
Run! They 're catching up!
快飽，來了
What's going on?
怎麼回事
Dad, they've been following us
爹，那兩個人一直跟著我們
We're very scared
嚇死我們了
Old man, are there any girls here?
老頭，有沒有人打茶圍
What is it that you want?
你們想幹什麼?
Are there any girls?
有沒有?
Go away...
去…
What's the matter with you?
問問你有沒有打茶圍，你這怎麼了
Can't you see...
你們看清楚沒有
this is a tailor shop?
我們這兒是裁縫鋪
A tailor shop?
裁縫鋪
Though we live near a brothel...
雖住煙花柳巷
we're a respectable family
卻是良善人家
One's wish can be fulfilled
心想事成
Heaven and Earth...
天靈靈，地靈靈
Are you blind?
瞎眼了你?死相
Lao Hai, come here!
老海，來
Are you calling me?
叫我?
Come here
來…
What is it?
什麼事
L"ll sell you a few pieces of chinaware.
賣給你幾樣瓷器
Have you got anything good?
你有什麼好瓷器
Are they Tang Dynasty's chamber pot
又是唐朝的夜壺
or queen's Jade urinal again?
西太后的翡翠尿盆呀
You must be joking. Take a look!
笑話，好東西呀，過來
Erotic figurines
避火的春意圖
Wait
你等等
What do you think?
怎麼樣
It's a bit coarse
粗了點
And this. It's different
還有您看這個，這個跟那個不一樣
Look
您看看
Very mediocre
普通嘛
Let me look at this one
看看那個
This is good
這個好
Is this good?
這個好不好?
So so
說不上好
This new Jiang Xi chinaware
這些個全是江西瓷的新貨嘛
How much are they?
要多少錢
That and that
這個整，這個零
You sell them as antiques?
您這個當古董賣呀
I'll offer you this amount
就這個數
Do you think it's rubbish?
您怎麼當破爛收呀
No can do?
不行呀
You must pay me this amount at least
最少你得給我這個數
Ok, it's settled
好，就這樣了
Ok, it's sold
好了…賣了
Baby, where are you going?
寶貝，哪兒去呀?
Disgusting!
討厭
What is there to see?
看什麼
You are too young to look at that
這麼小你就不學好
It's bad for your eyes
看在眼裏撥得出來嗎你?
What are you doing?
幹什麼嘛
Don't slap on the face,
don't scold mercilessly
打人不打臉，罵人不罵短
You slapped me on my face!
瞧你這一巴掌
No more nonsense. Back to work
少廢話，幹活
What happened?
怎麼了
Mr. Pan, this young fellow is so bad
潘老闆，這小兔崽子，人小心大
He even left his work just to have a look
看見了婊子，連活都不做了
Get back to work, you little bastard
幹活，這小王八蛋
Did you find my medicine?
我托您弄的藥怎麼樣
Yes, this will bring you satisfaction
找到了，這回包你滿意
This medicine is called Xian Ling pi
這藥叫僊靈脾
It comes from the sheep of Szechuan
是四川北部一種叫淫羊做的
These sheep make love 100 times a day
這種羊呀，一天交合一百遍
It will turn you on
真能上羊勁
It's also named Epimedium Macranthum
所以又叫淫羊霍
This medicine is very efficacious
吃下去是立竿見影
...and would make you a he-man
包你雄赳赳氣昂昂
You'll make your wife happy
你是揚眉吐氣，大嫂子是洋洋得意
Really? I'll want a refund
if it doesn't work
你說得這麼好聽，吃了不靈不給錢
You can get your money back
if it doesn't work
當然，當然了，不靈不要錢
Take 4 of the black ones.
They're are stomach pills
這黑的是胃藥，每次吃四粒
Take 1 of the golden one.
It's an aphrodisiac
這金的是淫羊霍，最多吃一粒
Only one?
才吃一粒
Yes, one is more then enough
別看吃一粒，大嫂子就受不了了
I heard you locked your wife up at home
對了，聽說你一出門
...before you went out?
就把大嫂子鎖在屋裏了
Yes, indeed
你不知道呀
Living as we do near a brothel,
住在煙花柳巷，牛鬼蛇神的地方
we must watch out
不小心點不行呀
If some philanderers should come here
要是來幾個下三爛，摸上了門
to ask for hostesses,
拿我們家當窯子，他硬要打茶圍
it'd take time to explain to them
有理纏不清，還是鎖上點好
Feng, why are you moving out?
老馮，怎麼?搬家了
Buddy, we've got no choice
兄弟，不說你不知道
My daughter's growing up
姑娘大了，不搬不行
Yesterday she went out with my wife
昨兒個大姑娘跟著她媽去買菜
Two guys followed her up here,
回來後面跟了倆
and asked for hostesses
硬要進屋裏來打茶圍
I have to move now
您說我不搬行嗎
Why don't you put something on your door?
門口寫上點嗎?
I've put up a pair of scrolls like you
是呀，我也跟您學，寫了副對聯
Though we live near a brothel...
雖住煙花柳巷
This is a respectable family
卻是良善人家
Did you inscribe something horizontally?
對，有橫批嗎
Yes. One's wish can be fulfilled
有呀，心想事成
Isn't that enough?
不就行了嗎
Enough? Yesterday morning...
行了?昨天早上我一看
some mischief-makers tampered with it
不知道是哪個王八蛋把橫批改了
How?
改了?
How they tampered with it?
怎麼改的
Come here. Come with me
您過來…跟我去看看
Come with me
您跟我過來
You can have it if you pay
錢多也成
Darling...
家裏的
Darling, where are you?
家裏的，哪兒去了?
Darling
家裏的
Darling...
家裏的…
Why didn't you answer me?
我叫你，你怎麼不應應
I thought you were out
我還以為你不在家，出去了呢
Out? I'm locked in, as usual
出去?大門上鎖，二門加拴的
Where can I go?
你叫我上哪兒去呀
Do you think I'm a spirit?
你真當我是魂靈呢
What's the matter with you?
吃槍藥了?
If you don't trust me
整天疑神疑鬼的
always be so suspicious
這麼小心眼想不開
Why did you marry me?
娶老婆幹什麼
If I really wanted,
I could cheat on you...
我告訴你，你老婆要是想偷人哪
even if you were to carry me on your back
你就是把她背在背上，她照樣偷
I didn't mean that
你聽我說嘛，誰說你偷人來著
But as we live here,
住在這種鬼地方
we must be careful
你不招貓，他們會來逗狗
What? Haven't you heard that...
逗狗
unless a bitch wags her tail,
你沒聽說過母狗不搖尾巴
no dogs dare to come close to her?
公狗也沒膽子上
I'm not afraid of anything
老娘走得正行得正，什什麼
You may not be afraid but I am
你當然不什了，我什
Come to meet the guests
見客了
Do you hear that?
你聽聽，你聽聽
Dammit, this place sucks
真他媽的這種破地方
Are you our new neighbour?
這位，您是新搬來的吧
Yes. I am Deng Xiao-Xian
是…我姓鄧，鄧小賢
Deng Xiao-Xian? Donkey Deng Xiao-Xian?
鄧小閒?潘驢鄧小閒呀
No, just Deng Xiao-Xian
不…鄧小賢，聖賢的賢
Not Donkey Deng Xiao-Xian
不是空間的閒
I'm pan Lao Hai. Do you mount paintings?
我叫潘老海，怎麼你是裱畫的
Yes, I am new at the job
對了…我是初學乍練的
We are neighbors now
以後街坊鄰里的
I need your help to recommend some work
還要請您多照應了
You're too modest
你就甭客氣了
Are you a new tenant?
新搬來的
This is my wife; Mr. Deng
我家裏的，鄧先生
Mr. Deng
鄧先生
No need to be so formal
大嫂子，你別這樣稱呼
Just call me Xiao-Xian
叫我小賢好了
We're neighbors. I need your help
以後咱們是街坊，您多照顧
You're welcome.
We ought to help each other
甭客氣，魚幫水，水幫魚
A neighbor is closer than a relative
遠親不如近鄰
Go... go to work
去…幹活去
You're too modest
您忙您的吧，甭客氣
Very kind of you
真周到
My stomach aches. Bring me a pill
胃藥，萬應錠…快
You finished them all, right?
萬應錠不是吃完了嗎?
Look in my shoulder bag.
Get me four, hurry
在褡鏈子裏，拿四顆，快
Where did you get these?
你在哪兒給我拿的藥
Just this box in your bag
就一盒嘛
What's the matter with you?
你怎麼了?怎麼了
You gave me the wrong pills
你給我吃錯藥了
That was Epimedium Macranthum
你給我四顆淫羊霍呀
What difference does it make?
什麼陽火陰火的?敗火就成了嘛
What are you trying to do?
你幹什麼
I... I want you!
我…我要你的命
What's the matter with you?
幹什麼嘛你
What are you trying to do? You'll kill me
幹什麼你?你這要命的
You bothersome
死鬼呀你
Higher
高一點
Move
動呀
Higher, Quick, Higher
高一點…快，高點
Higher
高點…
再高點
Quick, Move
快，動
Look carefully and learn
你們看著，學著點
You're hopeless.
If you don't take the pills,
真沒用，吃了藥一條龍
you're good for nothing
不吃藥一條蟲，德性
Darling, aren't you exhausted?
我說家裏的，你一點都不累呀
Exhausted? No, not at all
累?就憑你那兩下子，門兒都沒有
You're really fantastic
我真服了你，你真行
You must be careful. Don't you know
你當心點，你沒聽說
...how my ex-husband died?
我以前那個老公是怎麼死的
How?
怎麼死的
He took some sort of aphrodisiac
還不是吃了一粒春藥
It was called Yi Gan Liang or somethin'
叫什麼…一桿亮
Before dawn he died of apoplexy
沒等到天亮就中風死了
Apoplexy
馬上風呀
Yes
可不是嘛
You must not take any more medicine...
所以我叫你不要亂買藥吃
no matter what you do
別說你這幾手
Even my late husband, a martial artist,
就是以前我那死鬼老公開武館的
who was dubbed the invincible fighter...
外號叫做打遍天下無敵手
could not outlast me
在我身上照樣就過不了關
You're really something
真有一套
Something?
一套?
There are altogether 365 variations
百六十五套，套套不同
Beware, you may also die in my bed
當心點，當心你死在我身上
Then I'll be notice
我去拍電影
Is your wife out?
怎麼，大嫂子也出去了
No, she's at home, doing the laundry
沒有，跟家洗衣服呢
Then why...
那你
Living in this neighborhood...
住在這種下三爛的地方
it's better to have the door locked or...
還是鎖上點好，不然
That's right, your wife is indeed
very pretty
對，不然大嫂長得跟天僊似的
Looking for a hooker, if someone...
要有人楞進屋裏打茶圍
breaks into your house, you'd be a pimp!
那你不成了大茶壺了
Sorry! Sorry!
對不起
Have you eaten?
吃飽了
Then why don't you go to work?
吃飽了裱畫去
Damn fool!
婊子養的，什麼玩意
Can't you keep your dirty mouth shut?
吃人飯不拉人屎，滿嘴噴糞
I have an idea
我倒有個主意
That would stop him...
免得那個活王八
bothering me again
再吃春藥惹我的火
We'll find a witch...
不如咱們找那個跳大神的
to help us trick him
捉弄捉弄他
How?
怎麼捉弄法?
You arrange with the witch
你去跟巫婆子合計好
...to come and treat me
請她來給我看病
What for?
看病，你有什麼病呀
I'll pretend to be sick
沒病，不會裝病呀
I'll tell her that...
我就說呀
I'm possessed by my ex-husband's spirit
被我那個死鬼丈夫給迷住了
She can tell him not to touch me again
叫他不能再沾我的身
As he's so fond of sex,
那個活王八色迷瞪眼的
not one day can he do without a woman
天不搞都不行
You can introduce him...
你就介紹隔壁那個老鴨子
the procuress from next door
「滿床飛」給他
He sure will be satisfied
保管他稱心如意
Then we can do what we like
咱們就如意稱心了
How do we do what we like?
咱們兩怎麼如意稱心呀?
Idiot, we'll do the same
傻小子，他去滿床飛
...as he does
咱們倆來個飛滿床
I'm going down from a high mountain
我是緊打鼓，慢打鞭
I take a close look
撥雲頭，下高山
...from the high mountain,
高山之上，我仔細觀，仔細觀
and see dark smoke over the pans'
潘家院裏起黑煙，起黑煙
It portends evil
這團黑煙不等閒
Something bad is going to happen
掐指一算有禍端
Mrs. Pan is possessed by her late husband
呂氏她的死鬼丈夫把身纏，把身纏
Devil, just tell me
叫聲死鬼你聽言
...what is it that you seek
要吃要穿你只管講
and I'll give it to you
要金要銀當面談
You must quit making any more mischief
不能為非又作歹
Stop haunting your wife
你無故把人纏，你無故把人纏
I want nothing from you
我不要吃來不要穿，不要穿
I don't care about money
金銀財寶堆成山，我視等閒
But my wife has remarried,
呂氏她不該又改嫁
I can't go to heaven
叫我的鬼魂成不了僊
My spirit is restless...
嫁給別人我不管
for her husband was my enemy
前世他與我仇深似海，冤似山
Who's your enemy? I don't even know you
我跟你認都不認識，哪來的冤呀
You used sweet words to deceive me
你花言巧語將我騙，將我騙
...and cheat me out of my money
在我身上賺過不少錢
I want to give you three kicks
恨起來踢過你三飛腳
You better pay attention
你跟我竟耍太極拳
Now promise me three things...
如今我要求事三件
or I'll bump you off
否則我叫你一命染黃泉
It's okay if the three requests
are reasonable
有理不什你事三件
If not, then don't be so unruly
無理你休要耍野蠻
First, 20 taels of gold
一要他黃金二十兩
20 taels?
兩條呀?
Second, 10 yards each of silk and satin,
二要他十疋綢來十疋緞
with new pattern
花樣要新鮮
Who shall I give them to?
我交給誰呀?
To the seer and she will fulfill my wishes
一齊交大僊，替我把願還
What about the third thing?
這第三件呢?
You sleep apart from your wife...
從今後你與呂氏分床睡
until I go to heaven
直到我成了僊
My goodness, when will you go to heaven?
我的祖宗，你什麼時候才能夠成僊
We'll do as you've told us
依你…都依你
You're an evil spirit
你是神歸廟，鬼回山
From now on make no further mischief
從今不准再作怪
...and no more haunting people
不准你無理把人纏
Or I'll forfeit your passport...
否則…我扣下你的身份證
so you won't get back to Hades
叫你回不了鬼門關
Water. Bring me a bowl of water
水，給我拿碗水
Have some water
來…喝點水
What did he say?
怎麼說呀
Don't you know what happened?
你全不知道呀
How could I know?
大僊跟鬼魂說話，我怎麼知道呀
The spirit said he wants 20 taels of gold
鬼魂說要二十兩金子
20 taels?
二十兩?
10 yards each of silk and satin
十疋綢十疋緞全送到你那兒去
Good
那好呀
The spirit also wants me
另外鬼魂他還說
to sleep apart from my wife...
我跟我家裏的不准同房睡覺
no making love
不准同床
Really?
真的
Yes
可不是嘛
Remember, you must do exactly as he said
你要記著，你要照方抓藥
Nothing less would do...
條也不能少
or the spirit will haunt you
到時候別說鬼魂不答應
Even the God can't help you
就是大僊也不依
Come out and meet the guests
見客
please
請…
Do you have any particular girl in mind?
兩位大爺，有熟的姑娘嗎
Tell them to entertain the guests
叫她們都出來見見吧
Come out and meet the guests
叫她們見客了
Okay
好
please sit inside
請裏面坐
Girls! Come and entertain the guests
我說前院後院的姑娘們，見客了
Coming
來了…
These are our most popular girls
我們這兒最紅的寶玉跟小紅
What do you think?
你看怎麼樣
They're good looking
不錯吧
That's enough
甭看了
Which one do you like?
你看哪個對眼
Frankly...
我看了半天了
none of them appeals to my taste
說真的，沒有一個對眼的
How about you and me?
我看就咱們兩個吧
You must be joking
大爺，別跟我說笑話了
I'm far too old
我們都這麼老了
The older you are, the more experienced
老的敗火呀
Naughty!
討厭
Right, this is perfect
對，單嫖雙賭
You both are a match made-in-Heaven
你們真是天生一對地設一雙
Shouldn't waste this lovely night.
I'll go now
別耽誤良辰美景了，我先走了
Don't go
你別走了
Listen
你聽我說
Look
你瞧瞧，真是
Disgusting!
討厭
Let me close the door
我先去關上門
Good
好
Now we can do what we like
這回可如意稱心了
Thank you
謝謝您了
Not at all
哪裏
Where have you been?
怎麼老沒來呀，死鬼